SANJEEWA RANULUGE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

STATUS

Living in Christchurch, New Zealand, on work visa (Partner of a Resident)

CONTACT

+642040698789

sbandara725@gmail.com

LinkedIn

Portfolio

Portfolio

GitHub

15A, Kenilworth Street, Addington, Christchurch, New Zealand

SKILLS

- Proficiency in JavaScript, Typescript, PHP, Python
- Experience with front-end Technologies such as ReactJs, NextJs, React Native, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Redux-Saga, axios, GraphQL, Formik, Material UI, styledcomponents
- Experience with mobile app UI development using React Native
- Experience with back-end development using PHP, MySQL
- Knowledge in Linux, REST APIs, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Docker, MongoDB
- Experience with version control systems such as GitHub and GitLab and Project management tool such as JIRA

OBJECTIVE

With 3+ years experience as a skilled and dedicated Software Engineer specializing in JavaScript, my objective is to utilize my expertise to create dynamic and responsive web applications that push the boundaries of user interactivity and enhance overall user experiences. With a solid foundation in JavaScript frameworks and libraries, including React and Node.js, I am committed to developing efficient and maintainable code that meets the highest quality standards.

.-----

WORK EXPERIENCE

Planned Career Break

February -2023 - To date

- Relocated to New Zealand to unite with my wife.
- Traveled and became accustomed to the culture.
- I'm working on personal projects to improve my skills, sharpen technical expertise, and improve problem-solving abilities.

Software Engineer

Aeturnum Lanka (Pvt) Ltd

October 2021 - January 2023

Project Domain: Health Care

Complete revamping for a legacy Electronic Medical Records EMR solution. The platform is designed for clinicians to prioritize the clinical experience. The result is a comprehensive suite that works with clinicians to deliver better care and compliance.

Front end development using Ant Design, ReactJS, Git, Jira, REST, JEST(unit test)

Responsibilities

- Developed several user interfaces and methods for functional requirements.
- · Researched and found solutions for technical issues
- Implemented the identified solution by coordinating the team.
- Covered the unit testing and application end-to-end testing.
- Investigated and used new technologies when needed.

Project Domain: E-Commerce Platform

Front end development using NextJS, Redux Toolkit, Material UI, Formik, Git, Jira, REST, Axios

Responsibilities

- Developed several user interfaces and methods for functional requirements and API binding.
- Code review
- Implemented the identified solution by coordinating the team.
- Maintained and improved the existing code bases and peerreviewed code changes.
- Investigated and used new technologies when needed.

- Problem solving and analytical skills
- Ability to work effectively in cross function teams
- Continuous Learning

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Industrial Statistics and Mathematical Finance

University of Colombo Sri Lanka

2014 Dec -2017 Dec

Hands on knowledge in Computer Science, Game Theory, Actuarial Mathematics, Statistics, Operations Research and Financial Mathematics

REFEREES

Referees will be provided upon request.

Software Engineer

TechLead International (Pvt) Ltd January 2021 – September 2021

Project Domain: E-learning platform

An e-learning platform to connect students and teachers

Backend development using $\mbox{{\bf PHP}},\mbox{{\bf Mysql}}$ and Front end development using $\mbox{{\bf Html}}$ and $\mbox{{\bf CSS}}$ and

Responsibilities

- Modified applications to resolved bugs, upgrade interfaces and improve performance.
- Researched and found solutions for technical issues
- Implemented the identified solution by coordinating the team.
- Design the software architecture and interfaces for the component to meet functional and performances requirements.
- Developed Mass communication method (connecting teachers and students) using a SMS gateway.

Associate Software Engineer

TechLead International (Pvt) Ltd December 2019 – January 2021

Project Domain: E-Commerce Platform

Front end development using Next.JS, Typescript, Rest API binding using GraphQL and Apollo Client

Responsibilities

- Successfully implemented the several features with REST API binding for web site (Shopping Cart feature and Authentication process)
- Developed User interfaces for the component to meet functional and performances requirements..
- Handled payment gateway for payment method

Online food delivery mobile application

Front end development using React Native, Redux, Redux Saga, axios Responsibilities

- Successfully implemented the several features with REST api binding for Mobile app
- Developed User interfaces for the component to meet functional and performances requirements..

Internship

Mobile App(e-commerce) - React Native

Responsibilities

 Developed several user interfaces and methods for functional requirements and API binding using Axios

Telicom multimeter projec

• Frontend development using PHP and Laravel-PHP framework, mysql

Brandix Apparel Solutions Limited

Feb 2018 - Aug 2018

Responsibilities

- · Time and action planning
- Coordinating frontend and plant through pre production meetings